Tatenda Chawanzwa

www.tatendachawanzwa.com

Languages / Technologies

info@tatendachawanzwa.com

www.github.com/shadrech

Be www.behance.net/tatendaChawanzwa

m www.linkedin.com/tatenda-chawanzwa

NodeJS, Javascript (ES6, React, Redux, D3.js), React-Native, Typescript, Jest, Sinon.js, Enzyme, react-testing-library, Mocha, Cucumberjs, Cypress, PHP (Laravel, Slim, Wordpress), GRPC, HTML, SCSS, GIT, Nginx, Apache, Linux OS, MYSQL, GraphQL, Postgres, DynamoDB, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Redis, Docker, Kubernates, AWS, JIRA, CircleCl

Software

Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch, Blender 3D, DaVinci Resolve, GNU Octave

About Me

Full Stack Engineer and speaker familiar with the entire engineering process from design to deployment. Strong design acumen is coupled with extensive knowledge of Javascript (Typescript, ES6, React, Redux...) alongside proficiency in the Adobe Creative Cloud and Sketch. Backend I have solid commercial experience with NodeJS (REST, RPC protocol, Express.js, Fastify.js...), various ORMs/ODMs (Sequelize, TypeORM, Mongoose...), GraphQL, comprehensive knowledge of PHP (Laravel, Slim, Wordpress), AWS (Api Gateway, Lambda, RDS, S3...), GIT, Nginx/ Apache, Docker and other devOps tools such as CircleCI

Experience

Eurostar - Full Stack Developer

December 2018 - December 2019

Contract role. Working on greenfield pricing engine for their packages platform. Helped build to MVP and then assisted in building further features used by services throughout the Eurostar organisation Stack included React, React-Apollo, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress, GraphQL, ExpressJS, Cucumber.js and Docker/CircleCl for Cl pipeline

Sky - Senior Developer

October 2018 - December 2018

Contract working on the NOWTV platform. Helped new integration with BT following a strict TDD/BDD environment. Stack included React, Redux, Enzyme, Sinon, Mocha, Cucumber.js

Infosum - Senior Frontend Engineer

September 2018

Small contract based in Basingstoke. Duties were to optimise data heavy dashboard on their analytics platform. Stack was React, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Typescript and D3.js. Contributed to their open source D3 library clreact-graph as part of my time there

90 Percent Of Everything - Full Stack Software Engineer

April 2018 - August 2018

Contract role. Stack included Node, GraphQL, gRPC, Golang, React, Redux, React-Apollo, Redux-Saga, Postgres, Elasticsearch and MongoDB. Instigated a major architectural change from data architects. Including adding new migrations to update Postgres tables, amending both GraphQL and gRPC servers to handle data from new architecture and other various code refactoring. Also contributed to frontend code, including creating a notifications component used throughout all apps, file upload component and various components to display and amend documents. Full stack work included creating a reports page where users could specify what

information they needed and generating a csv after collating the data from different data points on the backend (GraphQL, gRPC, various golang microservices). Backend work included adding ability to search for a new type of crewman. This encompassed updating the Elasticsearch mappings, adding new filters to the Elasticsearch query, amending protobufs for the gRPC servers and creating a new GraphQL endpoint for the frontend to talk to. Gained heavy exposure to their deployment pipeline which included Docker, Kubernates and Concourse

Applied Blockchain - Software Engineer

March 2018 - April 2018

Joined for a short period as company over hired front end devs (which was the main reason they had hired me for) and had more devs than the work required. Whilst there worked on a small React-Native project which enabled user to register on the Blockchain platform, being provided with a mnemonic key which was saved to devices Keychain (iOS)/ Key Store (Android). This also created a public and private address for the user using a in house library built by the Applied Blockchain team

Ruuby Limited - Software Engineer www.ruuby.com

February 2017 - March 2018

Was the sole in house developer along with the CTO. Stack comprised of Javascript (ES6/7, Typescript), React, React-Native and NodeJS (ExpressJS). Tasks range from redeveloping old React website front end with a new design, also updated api calls to talk to new NodeJS backend which I regularly contributed to (previously communicated with old Ruby on Rails backend). Also wrote/extended many of the microservices used throughout all applicationsReact-Native and NodeJS (ExpressJS). Tasks range from redeveloping old React website front end with a new design, also updated api calls to talk to new NodeJS backend which I regularly contributed to (previously communicated with old Ruby on Rails backend). Also wrote/extended many of the microservices used throughout all applications

Wrote multiple Lambda functions which were are responsible for issuing customer refunds, sending push notifications/emails, logging update data to audit system which I also built. Tasks include working with multiple databases such as Postgres, DynamoDB and the search engine Elasticsearch.

Also built the admin panel (React/Redux/NodeJS) which is used by the operations team to amend bookings/customers/therapists data, create/debit customers cards, add/crop therapist profile images etc...

Contributed to both ruuby customer app and ruuby pa app. Contributions include adding ability to select multiple treatments with quantity animation, adding recommender banner to therapists card (included backend tasks such as creating database columns, writing sql queries to retrieve data etc), and ability for therapists to add new treatments to an ongoing session. Apart from coding I also contributed to different graphical design/videography requirements. This included designing and coding the profile pages of the website and editing a Ruuby promo video which was played at the London Fashion Festival 2018

Freelance Developer/Graphic Designer

Mid 2015 - January 2017

Undertaken a range of projects with a stack comprising of PHP (Laravel), NodeJS, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Nginx, MySQL, Redis and the whole Adobe Creative Suite. Most notable project was for musical artists www.zoegracemusic.com (www.zoegracemusic.com (www.zoegracemusic.com (www.zoegracemusic.com (www.zoegracemusic-website). As the sole developer my responsibilities included

- Design entire site, including all digital banners/emails/icons/photographs (Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Canon 5D Mark III)
- Write entire code base using Laravel

- Build ecommerce platform using React.js, Redux, Redux-saga. Built custom CMS where store can be maintained/updated using technologies like FFMpeg/Redis/Socket.io. Laravel used for store API
- Setup server infrastructure. This included a Linode instance with Ubuntu and Nginx (LEMP Stack). Also setup ssl certificate for all sites running on the server (letsencrypt) and still carry out standard maintenance work on the server

Videographer

2011 - 2015

Have been involved in numerous video projects since leaving college, including being the co founder of ATS Productions, a media company I cofounded. We recorded weddings, conventions and generally any requested event. Graphic designer/videographer for record label CEM, where we've managed to accumulate more than 13 million YouTube views along with 100k subscribers

Open Source Contributions

- <u>Hacker0x01/react-datepicker</u>: Added time picker component
- PHP-FFMpeg/PHP-FFMpeg: Added feature to add metadata to audio files, including album/song artwork
- cognitivelogic/cl-react-graph: Added scaleLog support to D3 library

Education

Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera.

Certificate earned March 10, 2016

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/926H9224T27F

4 A-Levels

Beths Grammar School ('09) & Mayfield Grammar School ('15)
Design & Technology (A), Mathematics (A), Art & Design (B), Further Mathematics (C)

References

Available on request